Welcome. After last lecture, now we can officially enter our climb state by pressing our climb
欢迎。在上次讲座之后，现在我们可以正式进入爬升状态，只要按下爬升
action key and we can exit the climb state by pressing it again. And right now, we cannot
动作键就可以正式进入爬升状态，再按一次就可以退出爬升状态。而现在，我们不能
move our character. That's because we need to handle the climb physics once we are inside
移动我们的角色。这是因为我们需要在进入爬升状态后处理爬升物理学问题
of the climb state. And starting from this lecture, we'll look at how we can do that.
攀爬状态。从这个讲座开始，我们将看看我们如何做到这一点。
So you already know that we need to handle the physics and the movement, but what exactly
所以你已经知道我们需要处理物理学和运动，但是我们在这里到底需要做什么？
do we need to do in here? So inside of our custom climb physics function, there are several
我们需要在这里做什么？所以在我们的自定义攀爬物理函数中，有几个
things that we need to handle. So first, we need to process the climbable surfaces. We
我们需要处理的事情。因此，首先，我们需要处理可攀爬的表面。我们
use a capsule trace to capture the climbable surfaces in front of us. And during the climbing,
我们使用一个胶囊追踪器来捕捉我们面前的可攀爬表面。而在爬升过程中
we'll need to decide what to do with all those hit results. And same as walking or flying,
我们需要决定如何处理所有这些撞击结果。和行走或飞行一样、
we'll need to handle its velocity. So that includes the moving direction and its moving
我们需要处理它的速度。所以这包括移动的方向和它的移动
speed. Also, we'll need to handle the climb rotation. So for climbing, we'll need to move
速度。此外，我们还需要处理爬升的旋转。所以对于爬升，我们需要沿着表面移动
along the surfaces and the rotation is no longer the same when we are walking. We'll
沿着表面移动，旋转不再是我们行走时的样子。我们将
look at how we can handle this later. And last one, we'll need to snap our movement
我们稍后会看一下我们如何处理这个问题。最后一个，我们需要将我们的运动
to surface. If we don't do this, very likely we'll fall off from the surface when we're
到表面。如果我们不这样做，我们很可能在攀登时从地面上掉下来。
climbing. So this is something that we should handle as well. So let's look at how we can
攀爬时掉下来。所以这也是我们应该处理的事情。所以让我们看看我们如何能够
set this up. I'm going to close my project in here, then go back to the header file of
设置这个。我要在这里关闭我的项目，然后回到我的自定义移动组件的头文件中。
my custom moving component. So first, there's one function that we need to override. I'm
我的自定义移动组件的头文件。首先，有一个函数是我们需要覆盖的。我将
going to go back to this U character moving component. And in here, I'm going to search
回到这个U字形移动组件。在这里，我将搜索
for the function physics custom. So this is the function that we need to override in order
找出函数physics custom。所以这就是我们需要覆盖的函数，以便
to implement the climb physics. I'm going to copy this and I'm going to paste it inside
来实现爬升物理学。我将复制这个，并将其粘贴到里面去
of the header file. And mark this one as override as well. And while I'm at it, I'm also going
的头文件。把这个也标记为重写。当我在做这个的时候，我也要
to give it a region, same as these functions below. So above it, I'm going to type pound
给它一个区域，和下面这些函数一样。所以，在它上面，我将键入pound
region. And for this region, I'm going to call it overridden functions. And I'm going
区域。对于这个区域，我将把它称为重写函数。而我要
to place all these three functions inside. Then I'm going to create a function body under
将所有这三个函数放在里面。然后我将在下面创建一个函数体
this own movement mode changed. So place it in here. So inside of this function, first
这个自己的运动模式改变了。所以把它放在这里。所以在这个函数中，首先
thing I'm going to check, so if is climbing is true. So that means we are indeed inside
我要检查的是，如果爬升是真的。所以这意味着我们确实在
of our climbing state. Then we'll need to handle the physics in here. And outside of
我们的爬升状态。然后，我们需要在这里处理物理学问题。而在
this if check, I'm going to call the super version of this function. So copy these and
这个if检查之外，我将调用这个函数的超级版本。所以复制这些并
paste it in here. Then delete these two types. And for handling the physics, I like to create
把它粘贴到这里。然后删除这两种类型。对于处理物理问题，我喜欢创建一个
a separate function for it. So go back to my header file. I'm going to place that function
一个单独的函数。所以回到我的头文件中。我将把这个函数放在
inside of this climb core. So this function is going to return void. I'm going to call
放在这个攀登核心里面。所以这个函数将返回无效。我将把它称为
it physics climb. And it's going to have the same input parameters as this physics custom.
它是物理学攀登。它的输入参数将与这个物理学的自定义参数相同。
So copy these two and paste them in here. Then I'm going to create a function body, place
所以复制这两个并把它们粘贴到这里。然后我将创建一个函数体，把这个函数放在
this function under stop climbing. So place it in here. And first thing I'm going to call
这个函数放在停止爬升下面。所以把它放在这里。首先我将会调用
this function. So move back to this physics custom. I'm going to call the function physics
这个函数。所以移回这个物理学定制。我将调用这个函数物理学
climb. And pass in these two input parameters. All right, that's the basics app. And go back
攀登。并传入这两个输入参数。好了，这就是基本的应用程序。然后回到
to this physics climb. So what exactly do we need to do in here? If we were to write
到这个物理学爬升。那么，我们到底需要在这里做什么呢？如果我们要完全从头开始写
all of those physics code completely from scratch, there will be something very complicated
所有这些物理代码完全从头开始，将会有一些非常复杂的事情
to do. And luckily for us, inside of that pairing class, there are some co-examples
要做的事情。而幸运的是，在这个配对类里面，有一些共同的例子
that we can use. So I'm going to go back to the header file. And I'm going to go back
我们可以使用。所以我要回到头文件中去。我将回到
to this UCharacterMoving component. And in here I'm going to search physics flying. So
到这个UCharacterMoving组件。在这里我将搜索物理飞行。所以
I'm going to borrow some of the code from this function. So I'm going to select this
我将借用这个函数的一些代码。所以我将选择这个
function and press F12 to go to its function body. And I'm going to copy all of the lines
函数，然后按F12进入其函数主体。我将复制这个函数中的所有行
inside of this function. So in here, then I'm going to copy them. And I'm going to paste
这个函数里面的所有行。所以在这里，我将复制它们。然后我要把它粘贴到
it to our physics climb function. And I'm going to scroll up. And don't worry if this
粘贴到我们的物理学爬升函数中。然后我将向上滚动。不要担心，如果这
looks intimidating. All we need to do now is we just need to remove some of the lines
看起来很吓人。我们现在需要做的是，我们只需要删除一些我们不需要的线条
that we don't need. So after some testing and a few iterations, I found out there are
我们不需要的线条。因此，经过一些测试和几次迭代，我发现有
only a few lines that we need to keep in order to have a working physics. So first we need
只有几行是我们需要保留的，以便有一个工作的物理学。所以首先我们需要
to keep this if check, then keep this function. So this one restores the additive group motion.
保留这个if检查，然后保留这个函数。所以这个函数恢复了加法组的运动。
And inside of this if check, so these lines are for the flying. We don't need them. I'm
而在这个if检查里面，这些线是为飞行准备的。我们不需要它们。我将
going to delete them. And for this calc velocity, there are two things that we need to change.
我要删除它们。对于这个计算速度，有两件事我们需要改变。
So you can see the second input parameter is the friction and I'm going to pass in 0.F.
所以你可以看到第二个输入参数是摩擦力，我将传入0.F。
So during climbing, I don't want any friction. And this function here, this is another one
所以在爬升过程中，我不希望有任何摩擦。而这个函数，这是另一个
that we need to change. So this is the speed for breaking the set of vibration. And for
我们需要改变。所以这是打破一组振动的速度。而对于
that I'm going to create another variable that we can adjust inside of blueprint. So
我将创建另一个变量，我们可以在蓝图中调整。所以
go back to the header file and scroll down. I'm going to first hide this climb core and
回到头文件并向下滚动。我将首先隐藏这个爬升核心和
expand this climb BP variables. So I'm going to copy this U property and I'm going to paste
展开这个爬升BP变量。所以我将复制这个U属性，并将其粘贴到
it in here. So it's going to be another float. I'm going to call it max break climb deceleration
它在这里。所以它将是另一个浮动值。我将把它称为最大断裂爬升减速度
and give it a default value 400.F. Then I'm going to fill in this variable in there. So
并给它一个默认值400.F。然后我要把这个变量填进去。所以
paste it in here. I have a typo here. I'm going to fix that. All right, next line, we do need
把它粘贴到这里。我这里有一个打字错误。我要去修正它。好了，下一行，我们确实需要
to keep this apply group motion to velocity. Later we'll need to rely on group motion to
来保持这个应用于速度的群组运动。以后我们将需要依靠群体运动来
achieve a lot of things. And we don't need these two variables. So I'm going to delete
来实现很多事情。而我们不需要这两个变量。所以我要删除
them and we do need to keep these three lines and we do need to keep this function. So this
而我们确实需要保留这三行，我们确实需要保留这个函数。所以这个
is the function that actually moves our character and scroll down. So these lines here, they
是实际移动我们的字符和向下滚动的函数。所以这里的这几行，它们
are for the flying mode. I'm going to delete them and I'm going to move these two lines
是用于飞行模式的。我将删除它们，并将这两行移出
out and paste them inside of this if check. And format them a little bit. Then delete
并把它们粘贴到这个if check里面。并把它们的格式化一下。然后删除
this if check and we no longer have this variable. So I'm going to delete this one and that's
我们就不再有这个变量了。所以我将删除这个变量，这就是
pretty much it. This is all the boilerplate physics code that we need and I'm going to
基本上就是这样。这就是我们需要的所有模板物理代码，我要开始写一些注释。
start writing some comments. So right below this if check in here, we need to process
开始写一些注释。所以在这个if check下面，我们需要处理
all the climbable surfaces info. So that includes getting all of those information we need and
所有可攀爬表面的信息。所以这包括获取所有我们需要的信息和
perform some calculations. And the next thing that we need to do in here, we need to check
进行一些计算。接下来我们需要做的事情是，我们需要检查
if we should stop climbing. So there's no point in doing all of these things below if
我们是否应该停止爬升。所以，如果我们不需要攀登，那么做下面这些事情就没有意义了。
we don't need to climb. So this is the second thing that we need to do. And instead of this
我们不需要攀登。所以这是我们需要做的第二件事。而不是这个
calc velocity in here, we need to define the max climb speed and acceleration. We'll look
计算速度，我们需要定义最大爬升速度和加速度。我们将看看
at how we can do this later and scroll down to this safe move updated component. So in
我们稍后再看如何做到这一点，然后向下滚动到这个安全移动更新组件。所以在
here we need to handle the climb rotation. You can see the second parameter here we are
这里我们需要处理爬升的旋转。你可以看到这里的第二个参数我们是
filling in the updated components criterion. So this is where we should handle the climb
填补了更新组件的标准。所以这就是我们应该处理爬升的地方
rotation and I'm going to scroll down at the bottom of this function. So in here we need
我将在这个函数的底部向下滚动。所以在这里我们需要
to snap movement to climbable surfaces. And that's pretty much it. I'm going to compile
捕捉运动到可爬升的表面。这就差不多了。我将会编译
to see if there are any errors. Alright, I have a successful compile and in the next
看看是否有任何错误。好的，我的编译成功了，在接下来的
lecture we'll keep finishing this physics climb function. So these are the key elements
讲座中，我们将继续完成这个物理学爬升功能。所以这些是我们需要处理的关键因素
that we need to handle instead of the physics climb and feel free to use the code changes
我们需要处理的关键元素，而不是物理学爬升，请随意使用本讲座中的代码变化
in this lecture to help you with the boilerplate code for the physics. Alright, time for you
来帮助你处理物理学的模板代码。好了，现在是时候让你
to do the same and I'll see you in the next lecture.
做同样的事情，我们在下一讲再见。
[music]
[音乐]